Jason Xavier

Email: <u>jasxavier7@gmail.com</u>

Mobile: (+64) 21 298 8384

Address: Waitakere City, Auckland

GitHub:

https://github.com/jxav22

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jason-xavier-36b938218/

Career Objective

I would like to be involved in **full-stack development**, as I love coding and would be eager to develop a wide range of skills.

I am a fan of everything to do with problem-solving and innovation and I appreciate clean, elegant, workable solutions. In line with this, I like working collaboratively and sharing knowledge and skills to explore different ideas.

Skills Summary

Problem Solving

I have strong problem-solving skills, which I have developed throughout my degree. As part of my internship, I was introduced to the charting library 'echarts-for-react'. I analysed the pitfalls in the framework and created a complementary library to ease development. After being adopted by our team, we **doubled** our chart production capabilities.

Documentation

I have always placed a strong emphasis on writing readable, workable code. My focus on this allowed me to resurrect year old projects and upgrade them with the knowledge that I gained from my degree. An example of this are my Snake programs. I used my knowledge of **algorithm design**, **OOP**, and **SOLID** principles to evolve it into a modular, reusable, and resource efficient design which I have successfully implemented in both **JavaScript** and **C**.

Well organised

I have faced several major setbacks, from having covid-19, to managing the commitments of my job. To stay on top of things, I researched and implemented several time management strategies. I currently maintain a high GPA and am well regarded by my employers.

Experience Summary

Software Engineer Intern – SMX Email Cyber Security Experts November 2022 – February 2023

Software Development Team – Microsoft Student Accelerator New Zealand April 2023 - Current

ECSE Part II Assistance Centre Mentor – The University of Auckland Feb 2023 - Current

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) in Software Engineering

2021 - 2024

University of Auckland

- GPA: 8.0 (A average)
- Dean's Honours List 2022 **Top 5%** of Engineering Students
- Dean's Honours List 2021 Top 5% of Engineering Students

Detailed Experience

Software Engineer Intern – SMX Email Cyber Security Experts

- Worked in a team of 3 to make client-facing data analytics platform
- Ran weekly company-wide demos and incorporated feedback from key stakeholders and board executives

Software Development Team - Microsoft Student Accelerator New Zealand

- Curated a week-long curriculum, used by 150 students, to learn front-end web development
- Ran weekly office hours to help students complete a full stack web development project

ECSE Part II Assistance Centre Mentor - The University of Auckland

 Provided mentoring to students entering their second year of Electrical, Computer, and Software Engineering.

Technical Skills

JavaScript

 Gained extensive experience in JavaScript throughout my internship. Implemented production level code using the language, and related frameworks (Typescript, React, NodeJS)

Java

 Gained experience in Java through objected orientated design for several university projects.

Other languages I have used: Python, C, MATLAB and AHK.

Project Experience

Echarts Options

https://github.com/jxav22/EchartsOptions

- A simple library for creating the options object for an 'echarts-for-react' component.
- Allowed my internship team to **double** our chart production capacities.

Snake

https://github.com/jxav22/Snake

- A recreation of the classic game of snake for a MAX7219 LED dot matrix.
- My focus was on writing clean, understandable, workable code with extensive documentation.

Interests

I have a love for drawing and enjoy making pencil renditions of wildlife photography. I also play a lot of board games; my current favourite is "7 wonders duel".

References

References available on request